

<Function>

<help_tag>DFMC_iir_grpdelay.html</help_tag>

<help_path><helpdir>:\lvdfdttextmath.chm</help_path>

<name>iir_grpdelay</name>

<Description>

iir_grpdelay (MathScript RT Module Function)
Owning Class: singlerate 
Requires: Digital Filter Design Toolkit and MathScript RT Module
 
Syntax
[b, a] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd) 
[b, a] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd, w) 
[b, a] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd, w, r) 
[b, a, offset] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd) 
[b, a, offset] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd, w) 
[b, a, offset] = iir_grpdelay(n, f, e, grd, w, r) 

Legacy Name: iirgrpdelay 
 
Description
Designs an allpass, infinite impulse response (IIR) filter that approximates the group delay you specify. 

Inputs 
n - Specifies the order of the filter. n is an even, positive integer. 
f - Specifies the frequency points. f is a vector whose values increase monotonically between 0 and 1. 
e - Specifies the band edge frequencies. e is a vector whose values must also exist in f. 
grd - Specifies the group delay at f. grd is a vector of the same length as f. 
w - Specifies the weight of each frequency point. w is a vector of the same length as f. The default is a vector in which each element has a value of 1. 
r - Specifies the maximum value of the radius of any filter pole. r is a double-precision, floating-point number that must fall in the range (0, 1). The default is 0.9999. 

Outputs 
b - Returns the numerator of the designed IIR filter. b is a real vector with a length of n+1. 
a - Returns the denominator of the designed IIR filter. a is a real vector with a length of n+1. 
offset - Returns the group delay offset, which is the difference between the specified group delay and the approximated group delay. offset is a double-precision, floating-point number greater than zero. 

Examples
[B, A] = iir_grpdelay(10, [0, 0.4], [0, 0.4], [9, 0]); 
figure; 
grpdelay(B, A); 
 
[B0, A0] = ellip(7, 0.1, 60, 0.5); 
F = [0:0.4/256:0.4]; 
Grd0 = grpdelay(B0, A0, F*pi); 
[B, A] = iir_grpdelay(6, F, [0, 0.4], max(Grd0)-Grd0); 
Comp_b = conv(B, B0); 
Comp_a = conv(A, A0); 
figure; 
grpdelay(B0, A0); 
figure; 
grpdelay(Comp_b, Comp_a); 

Related Topics
iir_lpnorm 
iir_lpnormconstr 

</Description></Function>
